Peter Lubbers

Senior Program Manager, Google Developer Training

Summary

Peter Lubbers is a Senior Program Manager for Google Developer Training, in charge of all aspects of global developer training. In 2010, he started the San Francisco HTML5 User Group--the world's largest HTML5 user group with 14,000+ members.

Peter co-authored the book "Pro HTML5 Programming" (Apress, 2011) and he was instrumental in developing and delivering the cutting-edge HTML5 training curriculum at Kaazing.

Prior to joining Kaazing, Peter worked as an information architect at Oracle, where he wrote many books, such as the award-winning Oracle Application Server Portal Configuration Guide. Peter also developed automated HTML publishing and accessibility solutions. Four of these solutions are patented.

Before joining Oracle, Peter architected and developed the internationalized Microsoft Office User Specialist (MOUS) Testing Framework. In 2006, Peter was a technical reviewer for the book "Pro JSF and Ajax: Building Rich Internet Components" (Apress).

A native of the Netherlands, Peter served as a Special Forces commando in the Royal Dutch Green Berets. When he is not at home or out running triple marathons around Lake Tahoe you might see him jump out of a plane.

Specialties: Program Management, Developer Relations, MOOC Eduction, HTML5, Coffee.

Experience

Senior Program Manager, Google Developer Training at Google

October 2015 - Present

I head up the Google Developer Training team, focusing on developer training globally.

Senior Program Manager, Scalable Developer Programs at Google

October 2014 - October 2015 (1 year)

Responsibilities include running several scalable developer programs such as Google Developer Training (MOOC developer education), Google Developer Studio (video program for Google Developers YouTube channel), and scalable developer events (Google Developer Summits).

Program Manager, Scalable Developer Programs at Google

February 2014 - October 2014 (8 months)

Program Manager, Chrome Developer Relations at Google

June 2012 - February 2014 (1 year 8 months)

Senior Director Technical Communication at Kaazing

May 2008 - June 2012 (4 years 1 month)

Was in charge of all aspects of documentation and global training for Kaazing Corporation, headquartered in Silicon Valley, California.

Information Architect at Oracle

May 2005 - May 2008 (3 years)

Was in charge of many cross-functional documentation efforts such as the Oracle Application Server Developer's Guide for Microsoft Office and worked extensively on enterprise deployment, performance, and security documentation.

Also played an instrumental role in documentation production process automation and created several automated HTML and online help publishing solutions that were deployed company-wide (two of these solutions are now patented and another two are patent pending).

Principal Technical Writer at Oracle

April 2001 - May 2005 (4 years 1 month)

Wrote many books, such as the award-winning Oracle Application Server Portal Configuration Guide, focusing on enterprise web application deployment, web security, performance, high-availability, portals, Ajax, and SOA technology.

Principal Internationalization Product Manager at Oracle

February 2000 - April 2001 (1 year 2 months)

Ensured that Oracle Tools products were properly internationalized and localized in over 30 languages. Architected automation solutions that dramatically reduced costs and improved product quality.

Senior Training Developer (I18n)

December 1997 - February 2000 (2 years 2 months)

Worked on creating and internationalizing cutting-edge, concurrent training and testing software using Visual Basic for Applications. Architected and developed the internationalized Microsoft Office User Specialist (MOUS) Testing Framework.

Education

West-Friesland College (The Netherlands)

1985 - 1990

Honors and Awards

Award of Merit, Award of MeritHTML5, Global Program Management, Ultrarunning, Bungee Jumping, Lake Tahoe, Tahoe Rim Trail.

Peter Lubbers

Senior Program Manager, Google Developer Training



Contact Peter on LinkedIn